You are highly lifted up, Awesome God
You are highly lifted up, Mighty God
Thank you. You may be seated.
Thank you.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Hallelujah!
Good morning.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Yes! As it should be by Divine will.
Let me wish you Merry Christmas and a Happy New Year.
So, you know we are dwelling on "your faith will not fail".
I think that is what we are actually dwelling on.
Some of our actions - we sometimes thought it's faith, but it is not Biblical faith.
I think it is very important to look into that faith that is not Biblical.
There is other faith: We have faith in faith, faith in yourself and faith in others
like I have mentioned the last time.
Looking at those things that are not Biblical faith - but we see them as faith.
They are not Biblical.
When you know those things that are not Biblical faith,
you have a better understanding of what Biblical faith is.
I will take you to the book of Acts 14.
Let's quickly look at just a snapping healing that took place when Paul was addressing a congregation.
(Acts 14:8) "In Lystra, there sat a man who was lame."
That is, a man was there who was lame - could not walk.
(Acts 14:8) "He had been that way from birth"
He was born with it, with lameness.
(Acts 14:8) "and had never walked."
That is, the man had never, never walked.
He was born lame right from birth.
(Acts 14:9) "He listened to Paul"
This man was listening to Paul.
(Acts 14:9) "as he was speaking."
A lame man right from birth.
(Acts 14:9) "He listened to Paul as he was speaking.
(Acts 14:9) "Paul looked directly at him,"
At a lame man - listen to that.
(Acts 14:9) "saw that he had faith to be healed."
Hmm, listen to that.
A lame man who was born lame.
He was in the meeting when Paul was addressing the congregants.
(Acts 14:9) "Paul looked directly at him, and saw that he had faith to be healed."
Do you have faith to receive? That is the question.
What faith are they talking about here?
Do you have faith to be set free?
It means all of this demands for your faith.
It is not all up to Jesus; certainly it is not all up to you.
Your genuine willingness plus Jesus' ability.
It demands for your faith.
Paul saw in him faith to be healed.
Do you have the faith?
Here, I stand as Paul.
Can I see faith to be healed, to be blessed, to be delivered in you?
Can I? In you?
It calls for a question.
(Acts 14:9) "Paul looked directly at him, and saw that he had faith to be healed."
If I look at you, can I see faith?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Will I see faith?
What you are calling faith today is mere feeling.
You are disturbed.
Your heart is not at its best.
That is why we allow you to dance - to wipe away those troubles.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You ask, "Why dancing in the church?
Why so much time for dancing, dancing, dancing, dancing?"
So that you can forget where you are coming from.
Because where you are coming from is full of debts, trouble.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Your heart can only be at its best when you are happy - peace of heart.
And God can only attract you,
the Spirit of God can only attract you - attract your heart - join himself to you -
to bless you - when your heart is at its best.
So much trouble.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
We find ourselves in a generation without peace and patience.
There is no patience - hurry! hurry!
You time yourself. Imagine, you are coming to God, and you time yourself.
You have given a lot of appointments that "I'll be leaving here in 3 to 5 hours".
God is not one of those things.
You can time yourself to do business.
You can time yourself to visit a friend. You can time yourself to visit anyone.
You can time yourself to do anything.
But when it comes to God, disown it.
You don't time yourself to meet God.
This is where you miss the mark.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
In our various places of worship, we have time at which we should leave,
time to worship, time to sing in, to sing out,
time to do this, time to do that.
We don't time God because it's all about inspiration from Heaven.
We don't instruct God, we don't tell God when to start, how to start,
when to stop, when to start, when to begin.
This is where you miss the mark.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
"I'm here for a purpose",
"I am here to be healed", "I am here to be blessed".
This is bargaining.
You are bargaining with God.
Do you pay God?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
"I'm here to be delivered today."
This is bargaining.
Simply a bribe.
Whatever you now give, seems to be a bribe.
That is corruption.
You take that corruption to the house of God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Whatever you now give is, because you are here for a purpose.
Whatever you now give, is a way of saying, "I give this, You give me this".
We are all sitting as if we really mean business.
But it's because we don't have so much to do today.
Today is a free day, that is why you give it to God.
You only give to God what you do not need, time you do not need.
Your quality time - you can't give it to God.
You don't have any appointments today, that is why you are here.
You don't give your quality time to God.
If God continued to give you what He Himself did not need,
as you are giving change...
You know when you want to give your offering?
These are things you collected from the petrol station - change.
The money you collected from the conductor (public transport operators).
The money you collected from where you buy and sell.
That is the change you give to God.
If God continued to give you such change back in return -
what God did not need - what you do not need -
would you say He has blessed you?
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You believe you are serving God.
Are you serving Him with your quality time, your quality strength?
Let's look at what is not Biblical faith.
We say faith, we have faith; but you need Biblical faith.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You deny everything. When they ask you, "What is your problem?",
you prefer to say a different thing.
You don't tell people - until you are about to die.
Getting to the point of death, you can say it out.
Or when the doctors reject you and say, "No, this is above us".
Then, you run to God.
You deny the existence of a problem.
Faith is not denial.
Faith does not deny the existence of a problem.
There is a problem.
Even the Bible says, "In this world there will be tribulations. Cheer up; I have overcome".
There is a problem! Why should you deny it?
You can't deny it!
Everyone has limitations.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Faith is not denial.
Faith does not deny the existence of a problem.
There is a problem!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Everybody has a medical report somewhere.
Your medical record.
But when you are getting to the point of death, you run to God.
You are ready to say, "This is what I have",
"This is my problem".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You say you are a Christian.
A person has to recognise he is sick before getting healed.
He is sick!
And run to the Healer, the Saviour, before getting healed!
But at what point do you recognise you are sick?
When all hope is lost.
When you have spent all your fortune.
At what point, do you recognise you are sick and run to Jesus?
When all hope is lost and everything is gone.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Confessing or not does not change the fact.
Knowing facts about God does not change your relationship with Him.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
When you put the Word of God to work, eventually your circumstances are subject to change.
Put to work the Word of God.
Put to work.
Like last week when I was moving around - if not for the gift of prophecy -
meeting some people, they would come here and say, "I have fever".
By the time I am praying, I realise that this is HIV 1 and 2.
Until they get to the point of death, before they say, "Jesus is Lord!",
"He is my Healer".
Faith is not imitation, which is common among us.
Faith is NOT imitation!
It cannot be imitated!
It must arise in each person's heart, based on the Word of God.
It cannot be imitated.
But today, what is happening?
You see everybody doing the same.
Sometimes, God deals with people in different ways.
God will not meet you because you imitate what someone else did.
This is why it is a bit dangerous when you pick a textbook
and you read how to pray.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
The Holy Spirit helps us in our prayer.
When you take a textbook and begin to read how to pray -
"pray for deliverance", "pray for this", "pray for that" - no.
God will not meet you because you imitate what someone else did.
Tell your neighbour, "God will not meet you
because you imitate what someone else did".
That is, someone else prays, "In Jesus' name, in Jesus' name!"
After watching the way the person prays, you also get there and say,
"In Jesus' name, in Jesus' name!"
Remember, this one is being inspired to do so.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
You are not inspired to do so, you are only copying, you are only imitating.
Some of you will pick up a textbook and begin to read
"7 points of ways to pray".
You want to fast for 3 days because you read somewhere to do so.
The person has been inspired to do so.
Not you!
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God will not meet you because you imitate what someone else did.
God will meet you when you obey what He told you to do by the Spirit,
based on His Word.
When you take action in obedience to God, you will prosper.
When you take action in obedience to God, you will get it.
You will prosper.
Tell your neighbour, "God will not meet you, because you imitate what someone else did".
Like prayer, like fasting.
You say, "Somebody asked me to fast",
"This is the standard", "This is the traditional way", "This is the song to sing ",
"This is how to sing it out, this is how to sing it in",
"This is this, this is that",
"This is what they asked us to do",
"This is this" - this is a lot.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
God will meet you when you obey what He Himself told you to do
and He can only say it by His Spirit, based on His Word.
That is, taking action in obedience to God.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Three, faith is not an issue of ordering God around.
You know today, our prayer is to instruct God.
We always instruct God, "I need this. In the name of Jesus give me, give me, give me, give me!"
You don't mind whether it is His will to give you.
You don't even bother to know God's will before you ask.
And if you ask according to His will, He gives.
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Faith is not an issue of ordering God around.
When we pray, we instruct God what to do, what to give us
and when that is not given, we feel bad! It affects our faith.
Who knows what would have happened to you,
if your prayer for a better life had been answered?
A better life to buy the best car.
A better life to build a beautiful house.
A better life to become a governor, a minister, a senator.
Who knows what would have happened?
We are talking about those things that are not Biblical faith.
And we practice it; we say it is faith.
Many things you do, like many testimonies today,
people came out to say, "Yes, I ministered my Morning Water 4 times, saying 'Jesus! Jesus! Jesus!'".
You quickly write it down.
Why are you writing it down?
When you get your own, you now say "Oh, that man ministered it 3 times, saying 'Jesus, Jesus'".
You will now do your own too: "Jesus, Jesus, Jesus!!!"
Nothing happens.
The man that is talking may be inspired by the Holy Spirit to do so.
But you are not inspired.
You are only imitating this man.
You are an "imitator".
The SCOAN Sunday Service
Like many of us have books we read - "prayer",
"prayer for deliverance: turn this way, 'Jesus! Jesus!' Turn to the other side, 'Jesus, Jesus!'
Another side, 'Jesus! Jesus!'"
It get's frustrating when you do that and the prayer is not answered.
But you are imitating.
The man, somebody, wrote it.
The person has been inspired to do so - but not you!
You will not meet Jesus because you imitate what someone else did.
What someone else did is what you are reading.
Unless you receive from God in yourself...
You will meet God when you obey what God told you directly.
May God bless His Word.